## **Daniel Watson**

### Software Engineer

A dynamic and experienced software engineer with an extensive background in data analysis. With a deep focus on project management - demonstrated through both on-the-job project completion and through external training - organizational skills, problem-solving, and time management have been mastered. Passionate in further expanding knowledge and skills within the Software Engineering field.

- dkwatson522@gmail.com
- Westchester, NY, USA
- in linkedin.com/in/daniel-watson-mshi

## [] (914)552-2666

- danielwatson.dev
- github.com/dkwatson522

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## **Healthcare Analyst**Orthonet, LLC

02/2019 - Present

- Utilizes SQL to analyze and combine big data sets to aid organizational decision making and track program performance.
- Conducts client specific program refresh to generate 15% impact on claim intake vs savings ratio.
- Builds forecasting models for clients to track budget and performance variations for financial and operational metrics; Used as a base model to track COVID-19 impact on program.

### **Data Analyst** Orthonet, LLC

02/2017 - 02/2019

- Assisted in creating data visualization dashboards in Tableau to streamline data and provide interactive reporting for operational stakeholders; reduced requests to query data.
- Automated data pulls through stored procedures and database tables to expedite scheduled client reporting and increase efficiency in analysis.
- Applied data migration tools, SQL Server Integration Services (SSIS), to load or extract datasets for analysis.

## **Appeals & Denials Coordinator**

Orthonet, LLC

03/2015 - 02/2017

### **Mailroom Coordinator** Orthonet, LLC

04/2014 - 03/2015

### **EDUCATION**

## M.S. Health and Medical Informatics

**Brandeis University** 

09/2016 - 12/2018

Waltham, Massachusetts

# **B.A. Sociology** CUNY Queens College

### **SKILLS**



### PERSONAL PROJECTS

### Dunder Mifflin Employee Portal 🗗

- https://stark-mountain-68376.herokuapp.com/https://github.com/dkwatson522/dunder\_mifflin\_employee\_portal
- Created a full-stack web application utilizing Ruby, Ruby on Rails, React and PostgreSQL to mock an employee portal.
- "Employees" are able to create requests generating an email notification to their "Manager" to Approve/Deny requests.
- Utilized recursive relationship with user authentication to establish Employees - Manager relationship which enables employees to send an email to their manager when a new PTO request is created.

### Sugar Spell Mock Website

- https://www.sugar-spell.com/https://github.com/dkwatson522/sugar-spells
- Created a full-stack web application that makes use of Node.js, Express and MongoDB to showcase a candy business.
- Purpose was to gain a better understanding of connecting a web front end with a back end through the use of Express and MongoDB.
- Implemented authentication flow to allow the business owner to manage orders.

### Media Quiz 🗹

- https://www.mediaguess.com/ https://github.com/dkwatson522/dw-movie-guess
- Created a web application that utilizes API calls to create dynamic quizzes based on trending topics in entertainment.
- Utilized jQuery to take back user selections to provide feedback on the correct answer for the questions.

### **TRAINING**

#### All Aboard Bootcamp (03/2021)

Learned Ruby, Ruby on Rails, SQLite, Javascript, HTML and CSS. Worked on creating model, view, controller design pattern with a SQLite database.

### General Assembly - JavaScript Development (01/2020)

Studied JavaScript frontend fundamentals through Object Oriented Programming, Document Object Models (DOM), API calls and jQuery

#### INTERESTS

Sports Traveling Exercise

01/2010 - 12/2014